Guide to the Ralph I. Gifford Photographs circa 1910s - 1947
Oregon State University Libraries, University Archives
Ralph I. Gifford Photographs
circa 1910s - 1947
1935-1947
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center University Archives 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
P 218-SG 2
Gifford, Ralph I.
2.5 cubic feet, including 2089 photographs 17 boxes, including 2 oversize boxes, and 1 map folder
The Ralph I. Gifford Photographs consist of images taken by Gifford throughout Oregon, primarily during the 1930s and 1940s. The photographs depict many Oregon landmarks and scenes, including the Oregon Coast, Crater Lake, Mount Hood, the Wallowa Mountains, and the Snake River Canyon. The collection includes numerous images of sport fishing as well as several photographs of Native Americans. Ralph Gifford was the son of Benjamin A. Gifford and took over his father's Portland photography business around 1920. In 1936, Ralph became the first photographer of the newly established Travel and Information Department of the Oregon State Highway Department, a position he held until his death in 1947.
Biographical Note:
Born in Portland, Ralph I. Gifford (1894-1947) worked in his father's (Benjamin A. Gifford) photography studio as a boy and accompanied his father on photography trips around Oregon. He married Wanda Muir Theobald in 1918 and spent the last part of World War I in the U.S. Navy. Ralph took over his father's photography business around 1920 and sold it in 1928 to go into the motion picture business with F. C. Heaton in Portland.
In 1936, Ralph became the first photographer of the newly established Travel and Information Department of the Oregon State Highway Commission. His landscape views of Oregon's natural beauty were used for many years to promote tourism in the state. He also took motion pictures for the Highway Commission, including its 1941 color version of The New Oregon Trail, which was shown in every state in the U.S., and Glimpses From Oregon State Parks, released shortly before Ralph's death on June 23, 1947. His obituary, published in several Oregon newspapers in late June 1947, stated that "more than any other person, he is responsible for the tourist business in Oregon being an $83,500,000 business."
Ralph also took and sold photographs commercially; many of his commercial views were taken at the same time as his Highway Commission photos. His photographs could be purchased as postcards, view sets, individual prints, and photo-plaques. In a letter to the managing editor of U.S. Camera magazine, Ralph stated in 1943 that his work was "to visually educate the traveling public as to Oregon's scenic and vacation possibilities."
The Ralph I. Gifford Photographs consist of images taken by Gifford throughout Oregon, primarily during the 1930s and 1940s. Many of Ralph Gifford's landscape photographs complement those he took for the State Highway Commission, as they were taken at the same time. He extensively photographed the Oregon Coast, Crater Lake, Silver Falls, Mount Hood and Timberline Lodge, the Pendleton Round-Up, the Wallowa Mountains, and the Snake River Canyon. Many of his photographs were made into postcards or view sets, which were sold at souvenir shops throughout the state.
Gifford also photographed the Columbia River Gorge, Multnomah Falls, and the Columbia River Highway; the Oregon State Capitol and other state buildings in Salem; the Oregon Caves; highway bridges on the Oregon coast; and Oregon agriculture, especially orchards and ranches. Several Oregon rivers are depicted in the collection, including the Chetco, Imnaha, John Day, McKenzie, and Rogue Rivers as well as numerous Cascade Mountain lakes. Scenes of Portland, Brookings, and Salem are part of the collection. The collection includes numerous images of sport fishing and fishermen as well as several images of Native Americans, especially participating in the Pendleton Round-Up. Chief Clarence Burke, of the Umatilla Indians, is depicted in several photographs. Images of Gifford's wife, Wanda, and children are part of the collection.
The collection includes photographs Gifford took while stationed at Whiddy Island, Ireland, in the U.S. Navy during World War I. These images depict fellow servicemen, the local people of Whiddy Island, houses and structures, and landscapes and towns on the island.
The bulk of the collection consists of film negatives (853 items) and prints (902 items). Film negatives are predominantly 4x5 format; however, 5x7 and 8x10 formats are also included. The prints include 8x10 and larger sizes as well as postcard prints. The collection also includes 256 nitrate negatives, 22 glass negatives, and 56 color positive transparencies.
Many images in the collection are available online in several digital collections.
Collection is open for research.
The Ralph I. Gifford Photographs are arranged in 9 series: I. World War I Views of Whiddy Island, Ireland, 1918; II. Gifford Family, circa 1920 - circa 1930; III. Nitrate Negatives, circa 1910s - circa 1935; IV. Numbered Series, circa 1935 - 1947; V. Highway Commission Photographs, 1936-1946; VI. Postcard Photographs, circa 1935-1945; VII. Coastal Bridges, circa 1936; VIII. Un-Numbered Photographs, circa 1935 - 1947; and IX. Color Transparencies, circa 1937 - 1947.
The photographs were donated to the Oregon State University Horner Museum in 1986 by Ben L. and Beth Gifford.
The photographs were transferred from the Oregon State University Horner Museum to the University Archives in July 1996.
This is one component of the Gifford Photographic Collection (P 218) held by the OSU Archives. Other components are: Benjamin A. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 1); Ralph I. Gifford Motion Pictures (P 218-SG 3); Wanda M. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 4); Ben L. Gifford Photographs (P 218-SG 5); Gifford Collection Photographs by Unknown or Other Photographers (P 218-SG 6); and Gifford Collection Documentary Materials (P 218-SG 7).
Other collections containing Ralph Gifford's work include the Extension and Experiment Station Communications Photograph Collection (P 120), Clackamas County Jersey Cattle Club Scrapbook, Roland G. Holmes Collection of Oregon and Washington Postcards (P 283), Gerald W. Williams Collection, Edwin Russel Jackman Photographs (P 089), and the John E. Smith Collection.
Photos taken by Ralph Gifford for the State Highway Commission can be found at the Oregon State Archives in the records of the Oregon Department of Transportation.
Burke, Clarence.; Gifford, Wanda.; Ager, Cecil V.
Oregon State Capitol (Salem, Or.: 1938- ); Timberline Lodge (Mount Hood, Or.); Pendleton Round-Up.; Oregon. State Highway Dept.
Agriculture--Oregon.; Bridges--Oregon.; Fishing--Oregon.; Indians of North America--Columbia Plateau.; Lakes--Oregon.; Landscape photography--Oregon.; Parks--Oregon.; Waterfalls--Oregon.
Brookings (Or.); Cascade Range.; Chetco River (Or.); Columbia River.; Columbia River Gorge (Or. and Wash).; Columbia River Highway (Or.); Crater Lake (Or.); Hells Canyon (Idaho and Or.); Hood, Mount (Or.); Imnaha River (Or.); Multnomah Falls (Or.); Oregon--Description and travel.; Oregon Caves National Monument (Or.); Pacific Coast (Or.); Portland (Or.); Salem (Or.); Silver Falls State Park (Or.); Wallowa Mountains (Or.); Whiddy Island (Ireland)
Color transparencies.; Film negatives.; Glass negatives.; Nitrate negatives.; Photographic prints.; Photographic postcards.
Agriculture; Fisheries and Wildlife; Native Americans; Parks and Playgrounds; Public Works; Ranching; Sports and Recreation; Transportation; Women; Oregon; Salem; Photographs
- World War I views of Whiddy Island, Ireland, 1918; Series I; 47 nitrate negatives and 1 print
  Series I consists primarily of photographs taken by Ralph Gifford while he was stationed on Whiddy Island, Ireland, with the U.S. Navy during World War I. The images depict Gifford's fellow servicemen, the military installation, the local people of Whiddy Island, houses and structures, and landscapes and towns on the island. All of the images are nitrate negatives and are available online in the Best of the Archives digital collection. The series also includes one print, collected by Gifford, of the King of England visiting an American ship.
  - Airplane and pilot at Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Airplane hangers at Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Barracks at the Naval base on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Barracks at Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers in barracks at Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Bonane near Kenmare, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Building on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Naval buildings on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Buildings on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Church on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Dirt bank on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Dock on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Glengarrif, a town in the NE corner of Bantry Bay, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Hall decorated for Christmas on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Houses on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Irish girl on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Irish man on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Irish man on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Irish men on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Kitchen at the Whiddy Island camp, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Landscape on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Loading a ship at Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Loading ship on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Men at work, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Men at work, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Naval group picture at Whiddy Island, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Plane and pilot at the Whiddy Island base, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Sailors during Christmastime on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Ship at dock on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Snave Bridge, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldier at desk with "no smoking" sign, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldier and Irish man, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldier with Irish man on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers and wrecked plane, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Soldiers playing pool, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Stone fountain on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Tunnel on a pass between counties Cork and Kerry, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Tunnel on pass between counties Cork and Kerry, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - View of barracks and hangers on Whiddy Island, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Whiddy Island barracks, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Woman on Whiddy Island, Ireland, with dog, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Woman on Whiddy Island, Ireland, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - Wrecked plane, nitrate film negative (Box 60)
  - "His Majesty - King of England Visits American Ship in British Waters", circa 1918 (Box 2)
    Photo by Denson.
- Gifford Family, circa 1920 - circa 1930; Series II; 18 glass negatives and 5 nitrate negatives
  Series II consists of photographs of Ralph Gifford's family, including his wife Wanda and children Ralph, Jr., and Benjamin L.. The series consists primarily of glass negative; it also includes several nitrate negatives.
  - Ralph and Wanda Gifford home?, E. 29th and Glisan, Portland, 3.5x5.5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - Ralph Gifford, Jr., circa 1920
    - In wash basin, 3 3.5x5.5 glass negatives (Box 15)
      Wanda Gifford in one image.
    - Weighing in at 16 lbs., 2 3.5x5.5 glass negatives (Box 15)
    - Lying on a blanket, 2 3.5x5.5 glass negatives (Box 15)
  - "Baby Ben" (Ben L. Gifford) in a wicker baby carriage, circa 1924; 5 4x5 glass negatives (Box 15)
  - Ben L. or Ralph Jr. on a tricycle, 1920s; 4x5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - "Ralph and Nils(?)" (Ralph Jr. and friend?), early 1920s; 4x5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - Wanda Gifford fishing from a raft in a river, 1920s; 4x5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - Wanda Gifford? working in the kitchen, circa 1920; 4x5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - One of Ralph and Wanda Gifford's children as a baby, 1920s; 4x5 glass negative (Box 15)
  - Ralph Gifford Family? in Oldsmobile, "Old Scout," Mt. Hood?, 1925; 4 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
  - Family group, including Benjamin A. Gifford, circa 1930; nitrate negative (Box 60)
- Nitrate Negatives, circa 1910s - circa 1935; Series III; 199 nitrate negatives and 12 prints
  Series III consists of nitrate negatives of a variety of subjects including individuals and groups, many participating in outdoor activities, and scenes in the Cascades and on the Oregon Coast. Most of the images of individuals and groups are unidentified; some of these may be of Gifford Family activities and outings. The negatives include some large format (8x10) images; however, many of the negatives are 4x6 or smaller snapshots. Prints for several of the negatives are also included. One image is available only as a print; no negative for that image is included.
  - A.A.A. 227 mile aeroplane view of mountains (Cascades), circa 1930; 14312; print and 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 2, 60)
  - Portrait of a young woman, 15189?; 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Ken Murry on old bicycle, 15192; 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Motorcycle policeman, Portland, circa 1930; 15267; 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Christofferson & deer; deer hunters with kill lashed to car, 15296-15297; 1 print and 2 8x10 nitrate negatives (Box 2, 60)
  - Railroad drawbridge, 6.5x8.5 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Models in tree at beach, circa 1930; 3 prints and 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 2, 60)
  - Four women on beach, 4x5 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Skiiers, Mt. Hood area?, 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Man and woman getting ready to ski, Mt. Hood?, circa 1930; 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Winter Morning on the Columbia -- Mt. Hood, partial 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Ray DeMeritt, 8x10 nitrate copy negative (Box 60)
  - Verne & May DeMeritt, nitrate negative (Box 60)
    Children.
  - Woman standing at base of rock formation, Columbia River Highway?, 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Man walking on trail in woods, 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Copy of a 19th century portrait of a man, 8x10 nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Boats in a harbor in the Far East?; "Copy of Carl Newberger's negative", 5x7 nitrate copy negative (Box 60)
  - Family group; wedding anniversary?, 6 prints and 7 8x10 nitrate negatives (Box 2, 60)
  - Oregon State Police trooper sitting with Native American, near Celilo Falls?, circa 1935 (Box 2)
    Perhaps Henry Thompson, son of Chief Tommy Thompson.
  - Unidentified snapshot images of people camping, hiking, etc.
    May include Gifford Family members.
    - Various family activities, circa 1910s; apx. 75 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - People hiking in snow; man hauling camera, 3 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Photographer; Ralph Gifford?, 3 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - People walking and camping in woods, 4 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Family group (Gifford?) swimming and picnicking, circa 1930; 11 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Farm scenes; older couple and grandchild?, 9 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Packhorses, hunting, fishing, camping, swimming scenes, 27 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Oregon Coast & Crater Lake, 16 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Panoramic views of mountain climber on glaciers, next to trees; views of mountains (Cascades?), 8 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    - Miscellaneous views, 18 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
- Numbered Series, circa 1935 - 1947; Series IV; 675 prints, 496 film negatives, 5 nitrate negatives, and 4 glass negatives
  Series IV comprises the bulk of the Ralph Gifford Photographs and consists of photographs made by Gifford throughout Oregon during the 1930s and 1940s. Only a few of the images are dated. The series includes views of Mount Hood and the Hood River Valley; the Columbia River Gorge, including Multnomah Falls; the Oregon Coast, especially the southern Oregon Coast; Crater Lake; the Pendleton Round-Up; central and eastern Oregon ranches; the Oregon State Capital building and grounds and other Salem, Oregon, scenes; Silver Creek Falls State Park; and the Wallowa Mountains. The images were assigned four-digit numbers by Gifford; similar unnumbered views are also included in this series. Original film negatives (primarily 4x5 plus some 5x7 and 8x10) are available for most of the images; multiple prints are included for some images. The series includes original photographs and master copy negatives for the Oregon in Miniature souvenir sets.
  - Car driving on forest road, 0100; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Forest with a fern floor, 0101; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Meadow at forest edge, 0104; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Barn and camp? at edge of a forest, 0105; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Rocky river bank, 0106; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Meadow and trees, 0107; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - River framed by trees, 0108; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - River, 0109; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    Same view as 106?
  - Shallow part of a river, 0110; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Tree lined river, 0111; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Boat dock with boats on river, 0113-0115; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Two cars parked near beach, 0116; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Ocean beach, 0117; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Ocean beach, 0118; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Sheep Homeward Bound; Evening scene on the John Day, 0118; nitrate negative (Box 60)
  - Rock cliffs on ocean beach, 0119; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Looking over bushes at beach, 0120; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Looking down cliffs at ocean inlet, 0121; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman looking over ocean bay toward a pier?, 0122; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Rock filled ocean cove, 0123; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Road going through mountains, 0124; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Mountain hills, 0125; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Forest floor, 0126; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman standing between two large trees, 0127; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman walking in forest, 0128; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Overlooking valley or coast, 0129; 3 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Forest covered hill, 0130; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - River at base of forested hill, 0131; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Car driving through forest, 0132; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Man walking through forest, 0133; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman fishing in river, 0134; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Forested hills, 0135; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Group sitting around fire on beach, framed by rock, 0136; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Woman standing in ocean pool, 0137; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Group sitting around fire on beach, 0138; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - People climbing rocks on beach, 0139; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Ocean wave coming to shore, 0142; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - People sitting in forest, 0143; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - People standing among myrtlewood trees on the Chetco River, near Brookings, Oregon, 0145; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    15 counts F11
  - Rock-filled ocean shoreline, 0146-0147; 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - Ship docking at sunset, 0483; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Tree lined road, 0508; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Caught fish sitting in front of fishing basket and fly pole, 0509; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - 3 men fishing in river, 0510; 2 prints and 8x10 negative (Box 2, 69)
  - Olof Rodegard, skiing down slopes of Mt. Hood, Mt. Jefferson in distance, 0511; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Scene near Dufur, Oregon, cattle grazing with Mt. Hood in background, 0512; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Mountains with a lake in foreground, 0513-0514; 8x10 negatives (Box 69)
  - Four men unloading boat into river, 1937; 0520; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Two men trying to keep small boat at shore, 0521?; 3 prints (Box 2)
  - Three men fishing around small boat in river, 0522? (Box 2)
  - Olof Rodegard, skiing, 0523; print and nitrate negative (Box 2, 60)
    Gelundesprung; ski jumping.
  - Truck with boat in bed driving through a forest; 3 men are sitting on the boat to keep it on the truck, 1937; 0537; 2 prints and 8x10 negative (Box 2, 69)
  - Fishing the Chetco River, Oregon; two men rowing down river, 0538; 4 prints and 8x10 negative (Box 2, 69)
  - Snow geyser from front, 0541; 8x10 negative (Box 69)
  - Hay stacks; Mt. Hood? in distance, 0555; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Cows on trail grazing, 0557; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Mt. Hood and rhododendrons, 0559; 4x5 negative and 4x5 copy negative (Box 8)
  - Boy and girl resting by tree gazing at ocean, 0563; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Ship docking at sunset, 0569; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Fisherman with equipment and catch of trout, 0571; 2 5x7 nitrate negatives (Box 60)
    Crater Lake?
  - The Oregon State Employee logo, June-July 1944; 0586; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
  - Woman holding up just caught fish, 0587; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - Ducks in creek flowing over roadway, 0588; 2 prints and 5x7 steroscopic glass negative (Box 2, 36)
    2 counts, F2, F11 stop; glass negative is broken.
  - Man on horseback looking at lake, 0593; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - "Neptunes Toll" wrecked fishing boat on the sand at Brookings, Oregon, 0601
    50th sec. F16; G filter
    - 4x5 negative (Box 8)
    - 5 prints (Box 2, 74)
  - "Temptation" girl and wave, 0602; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Realization" girl running from wave, 0603; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - Girl standing on beach with rock in background (Box 2)
    Same girl as in image 0603.
  - Two girls walking in surf on beach, 2 prints (Box 2)
    One of the girls is the same as in image 0603.
  - Two girls walking in surf on beach, 4x5 negative and print (Box 8, 73)
  - "#1 of Fore and Aft" twin boys looking over docks edge; front view, 0604; 4x5 negative (Box 8)
  - "#2 of Fore and Aft" back view of the twin boys, 0605; 2 4x5 negatives (Box 8)
  - "Silver Lining" clouds through treetops, 0607; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Phantom Ship" Crater Lake, July 16, 1941; 0608; 2 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Patriarch" old tree on edge of Crater Lake (Fortitude), 0609; 3 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Equinox" storm clouds and girl by old tree in 0609, 0610; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Patriarch" old tree on rim of Crater Lake (Box 2)
  - Summer Squall in Diamond Lake, Oregon, 0611; print and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
  - "Reflections" Grande Ronde River near Minam; Little Minam River from bridge at Minam, September 4, 1940; 0612; 7 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)
    4x5 speed graphic, superpan film, 1 100th. F22 G filter
  - "Cattle Country" near Burns, Oregon, 0613; 5x7 negative (Box 61)
    5x7 Eastman View Superpan film; 1/100 F22, G filter
  - "Days End," taken at Crown Point, Columbia R. Highway at sunset, November 6, 1940; 0614; 5 prints and 4x5 negative (Box 2, 8)